<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<class-scheme publication-date="2013-09-03" scheme-type="cpc" publication-type="official"> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="2" additional-only="false" sort-key="H" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">ELECTRICITY</text></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>These notes cover the basic principles and general instructions for use of section H. <subnote><note-paragraph>Section H covers : <subnote><note-paragraph>basic electric elements, which cover all electric units and the general mechanical structure of apparatus and circuits, including the assembly of various basic elements into what are called printed circuits and also cover to a certain extent the manufacture of these elements (when not covered elsewhere);</note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>generation of electricity, which covers the generation, conversion, and distribution of electricity together with the controlling of the corresponding gear;</note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>applied electricity, which covers : <subnote><note-paragraph>general utilisation techniques, viz. those of electric heating and electric lighting circuits;</note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>some special utilisation techniques, either electric or electronic in the strict sense, which are not covered by other sections of the Classification, including : <pre>
												<br/>- electric light sources, including lasers; <br/>- electric X-ray technique; <br/>- electric plasma technique and the generation and <br/>  acceleration of electrically charged particles or <br/>  neutrons;</pre> </note-paragraph></subnote> </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>basic electronic circuits and their control;</note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>radio or electric communication technique, including electromechanical transducers in general;</note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>the use of a specified material for the manufacture of the article or element described. In this connection, paragraphs 56 to 58 of the Guide should be referred to.</note-paragraph></subnote> </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>In this section, the following general rules apply : <subnote><note-paragraph>subject to the exceptions stated in I (c) above, any electric aspect or part peculiar to a particular operation, process, apparatus, object, or article classified in one of the sections of the Classification other than section H is always classified in the subclass for that operation, process, apparatus, object, or article, or where common characteristics concerning technical subjects of similar nature have been brought out at class level, it is classified, in conjunction with the operation, process, apparatus, object, or article in a subclass which covers entirely the general electrical applications for the technical subject in question;</note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>such electrical applications, either general or particular, include <subnote><note-paragraph>the therapeutic processes and apparatus, in class <class-ref scheme="cpc">A61</class-ref>;</note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>the electric processes and apparatus used in various laboratory or industrial operations, in classes <class-ref scheme="cpc">B01</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">B03</class-ref>, and subclass <class-ref scheme="cpc">B23K</class-ref>;</note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>the electricity supply, electric propulsion and electric lighting of vehicles in general and of particular vehicles, in the &quot;Transporting&quot; subsection of section B;</note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>the electric ignition systems of internal-combustion engines, in subclass <class-ref scheme="cpc">F02P</class-ref>, and of combustion apparatus in general, in subclass <class-ref scheme="cpc">F23Q</class-ref>;</note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>the whole electrical part of section G, i.e. measuring devices including apparatus for measuring electric variables, checking, signalling, and calculating. Electricity in that section is generally dealt with as a means and not as an end in itself;</note-paragraph></subnote> </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>all electrical applications, both general and particular, presuppose that the &quot;basic electricity&quot; aspect appears in section H (see 1 (a) above) as regards the electric &quot;basic elements&quot; which they comprise. This rule is also valid for applied electricity, referred to under 1 (c) above, which appears in section H itself.</note-paragraph></subnote> </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>In this section, the following special cases occur : <subnote><note-paragraph>among the general applications covered by sections other than section H, it is worth noting that electric heating in general is covered by subclasses <class-ref scheme="cpc">F24D</class-ref> or <class-ref scheme="cpc">F24H</class-ref> or class <class-ref scheme="cpc">F27</class-ref>, and that electric lighting in general is partly covered by class <class-ref scheme="cpc">F21</class-ref>, since in section H (see 1 (c) above) there are places in <class-ref scheme="cpc">H05B</class-ref> which cover the same technical subjects;</note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>in the above two cases, the subclasses of section F, which deal with the respective subjects, essentially cover in the first place the whole mechanical aspect of the apparatus or devices, whereas the electrical aspect, as such, is covered by subclass <class-ref scheme="cpc">H05B</class-ref>;</note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>in the case of lighting, this mechanical aspect should be taken to cover the material arrangement of the various electric elements, i.e. their geometrical, or physical, position in relation to one another; this is covered by subclass <class-ref scheme="cpc">F21V</class-ref>, the elements themselves and the primary circuits remaining in section H. The same applies to electric light sources, when combined with light sources of a different kind. These are covered by subclass <class-ref scheme="cpc">H05B</class-ref>, whereas the physical arrangement which their combination constitutes is covered by the various subclasses of class <class-ref scheme="cpc">F21</class-ref>;</note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>as regards heating, not only the electric elements and circuitry designs, as such, are covered by subclass H 05 B, but also the electric aspects of their arrangement, where these concern cases of general application; electric furnaces being considered as such. The physical disposition of the electric elements in furnaces is covered by section F. If a comparison is made with electric welding circuits which are covered by subclass <class-ref scheme="cpc">B23K</class-ref> in connection with welding, it can be seen that electric heating is not covered by the general rule stated in 2 above.</note-paragraph></subnote> </note-paragraph></subnote> </note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="3" additional-only="false" sort-key="H01" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H01</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"/> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="4" additional-only="false" sort-key="H01" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H01</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">BASIC ELECTRIC ELEMENTS</text></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>Processes involving only a single technical art, e.g. drying, coating, for which provision exists elsewhere are classified in the relevant class for that art.</note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H01B.xml" sort-key="H01B" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H01B</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">CABLES</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> CONDUCTORS</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> INSULATORS</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> SELECTION OF MATERIALS FOR THEIR CONDUCTIVE, INSULATING OR DIELECTRIC PROPERTIES </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">selection for magnetic properties <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01F1/00</class-ref>; waveguides <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01P</class-ref>; installations of cables or lines <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02G</class-ref>; </text><CPC-specific-text><text scheme="cpc"> printed circuits <class-ref scheme="cpc">H05K</class-ref></text></CPC-specific-text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>Group <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01B12/00</class-ref> takes precedence over groups <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01B5/00</class-ref> to <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01B11/00</class-ref>.</note-paragraph></note><note type="warning"><note-paragraph> The following IPC groups are not used in the CPC scheme. Subject matter covered by these groups is classified in the following CPC groups: <pre>
						<br/><class-ref scheme="cpc">H01B7/17</class-ref> to <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01B7/295</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01B7/18</class-ref> to <class-ref scheme="not-mapped">H01B7/28D</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="not-mapped">H01B7/34</class-ref> to <class-ref scheme="not-mapped">H01B7/34B3</class-ref></pre></note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H01C.xml" sort-key="H01C" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H01C</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">RESISTORS</text></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>In this subclass, the term &quot;adjustable&quot; means mechanically adjustable.</note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>Variable resistors, the value of which is changed non-mechanically, e.g. by voltage or temperature, are classified in group <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01C7/00</class-ref>.</note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H01F.xml" sort-key="H01F" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H01F</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">MAGNETS</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> INDUCTANCES</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> TRANSFORMERS</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> SELECTION OF MATERIALS FOR THEIR MAGNETIC PROPERTIES </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">ceramics based on ferrites <class-ref scheme="cpc">C04B35/26</class-ref>; alloys <class-ref scheme="cpc">C22C</class-ref>; </text><CPC-specific-text><text scheme="cpc"> construction of loading coils <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01B</class-ref></text></CPC-specific-text><text scheme="ipc">; thermomagnetic devices <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L37/00</class-ref>; loudspeakers, microphones, gramophone pick-ups or like acoustic electromechanical transducers <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04R</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>In this subclass, inductances and transformers are regarded as being &quot;for power supply&quot; if they are intended for this purpose even in systems operating at frequencies above 60 cycles/sec.</note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H01G.xml" sort-key="H01G" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H01G</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">CAPACITORS</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> CAPACITORS, RECTIFIERS, DETECTORS, SWITCHING DEVICES OR LIGHT-SENSITIVE DEVICES, OF THE ELECTROLYTIC TYPE </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">selection of specified materials as dielectric <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01B3/00</class-ref>; </text><CPC-specific-text><text scheme="cpc"> ceramics <class-ref scheme="cpc">C04B</class-ref></text></CPC-specific-text></reference></title-part></class-title></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H01H.xml" sort-key="H01H" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H01H</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">ELECTRIC SWITCHES</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> RELAYS</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> SELECTORS</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> EMERGENCY PROTECTIVE DEVICES </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">contact cables <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01B7/10</class-ref>; overvoltage protection resistors, resistive arresters <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01C7/12</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01C8/04</class-ref>; electrolytic self-interrupters <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01G9/18</class-ref>; switching devices of the waveguide type <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01P</class-ref>; devices for interrupted current collection <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01R39/00</class-ref>; overvoltage arresters using spark gaps <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01T4/00</class-ref>; emergency protective circuit arrangements <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02H</class-ref>; switching by electronic means without contact-making <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03K17/00</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph> <br/> Attention is drawn to the Notes following the titles of class <class-ref scheme="cpc">B81</class-ref> an subclass <class-ref scheme="cpc">B81B</class-ref> relating to &quot;micro-structural devices&quot; and micro-structural systems&quot;<br/></note-paragraph><note-paragraph>This subclass covers (in groups <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H69/00</class-ref> to <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H87/00</class-ref>) devices for the protection of electric lines or electric machines or apparatus in the event of undesired change from normal electric working conditions, the electrical condition serving directly as the input to the device.</note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>This subclass does not cover bases, casings, or covers accomodating two or more switching devices or for accomodating a switching device as well as another electric component, e.g. bus-bar, line connector. Those bases, casings or covers are covered by group <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02B1/26</class-ref>.</note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>In this subclass, the following terms or expressions are used with the meanings indicated : <pre>
						<br/>- &quot;relay&quot; means a switching device having contacts which are <br/>  operated from electric inputs which supply, directly or <br/>  indirectly, all the mechanical energy necessary to cause <br/>  both the closure and the opening of the contacts; <br/>- &quot;driving mechanism&quot; refers to the means by which an operating <br/>  force applied to the switch is transmitted to the moving <br/>  contact or contacts; <br/>- &quot;operating&quot; is used in a broader sense than &quot;actuating&quot; <br/>  which is reserved for those parts not touched by hand <br/>  to effect switching; <br/>- &quot;acting&quot; or &quot;action&quot; means a self-induced movement of parts <br/>  at one stage of the switching.</pre> These connotations apply to all parts of the verbs &quot;to operate&quot;, &quot;to actuate&quot; and &quot;to act&quot; and to words derived therefrom, e.g. to &quot;actuation&quot;.</note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>In this subclass, details are classified as follows : <pre>
						<br/>- details of an unspecified type of switching device, or <br/>  disclosed as applicable to two or more kinds of switching <br/>  devices designated by the terms or expressions &quot;switches&quot;, <br/>  &quot;relays&quot;, &quot;selector  switches&quot;, and &quot;emergency protective <br/>  devices&quot;, are classified in groups <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H1/00</class-ref> to <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H9/00</class-ref>; <br/>- details of an unspecified type of switch, or disclosed as <br/>  applicable to two or more types of switches as defined by <br/>  groups <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H13/00</class-ref> to <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H43/00</class-ref> and sub-groups <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H35/02</class-ref>, <br/>
						<class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H35/06</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H35/14</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H35/18</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H35/24</class-ref> and <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H35/42</class-ref>, <br/>  all hereinafter called basic types, are classified in <br/>  groups <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H1/00</class-ref> to <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H9/00</class-ref>; <br/>- details of an unspecified type of relay, or disclosed as <br/>  applicable to two or more types of relays as defined by <br/>  groups <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H51/00</class-ref> to <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H61/00</class-ref>, hereinafter called basic <br/>  types are classified in <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H45/00</class-ref>; <br/>- details of an unspecified protective device, or applicable <br/>  to two or more types of protective devices as defined by <br/>  groups <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H73/00</class-ref> to <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H83/00</class-ref>, hereinafter called basic <br/>  types, are classified in <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H71/00</class-ref>.</pre> However, details only described with reference to, or clearly only applicable to, switching devices of a single basic type, are classified in the group appropriate to switching devices of that basic type, e.g. <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H19/02</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H75/04</class-ref>; <pre>
						<br/>- mechanical structural details of control members of switches <br/>  or of keyboards such as keys, push-buttons, levers or other <br/>  mechanisms for transferring the force to the activated <br/>  elements are classified in this subclass, even when they are <br/>  used for controlling electronic switches.</pre> However, mechanical details directly producing electronic effects are classified in group <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03K17/94</class-ref>.</note-paragraph></note><note type="warning"><note-paragraph> The following IPC groups are not used in the CPC scheme. Subject matter covered by these groups is classified in the following CPC groups : <br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H01H33/575</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H33/56</class-ref> <br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H01H33/825</class-ref> &quot; <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H33/82</class-ref> <br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H01H33/835</class-ref> &quot; <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H33/83</class-ref> <br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H01H33/867</class-ref> &quot; <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H33/86</class-ref> <br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H01H33/873</class-ref> &quot; <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H33/86</class-ref> <br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H01H33/915</class-ref> &quot; <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H33/91</class-ref> <br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H01H33/985</class-ref> &quot; <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H33/98</class-ref> <br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H01H33/99</class-ref> &quot; <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H33/98</class-ref> <br/></note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H01J.xml" sort-key="H01J" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H01J</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">ELECTRIC DISCHARGE TUBES OR DISCHARGE LAMPS </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">spark-gaps <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01T</class-ref>; arc lamps with consumable electrodes <class-ref scheme="cpc">H05B</class-ref>; particle accelerators <class-ref scheme="cpc">H05H</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass covers only devices for producing, influencing, or using a flow of electrons or ions, e.g. for controlling, indicating, or switching of electric current, counting electric pulses, producing light or other electromagnetic oscillations, such as X-rays, or for separating or analysing radiation or particles, and having a closed or substantially closed casing containing a chosen gas, vapour, or vacuum, upon the pressure and nature of which the characteristics of the device depend. Light sources using a combination (other than covered by group <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J61/96</class-ref> of this subclass) of discharge and other kinds of light generation are dealt with in <class-ref scheme="cpc">H05B35/00</class-ref>.</note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>In this subclass, groups <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J1/00</class-ref> to <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J7/00</class-ref> relate only to: <subnote><note-paragraph>details of an unspecified kind of discharge tube or lamp, or</note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>details mentioned in a specification as applicable to two or more kinds of tubes or lamps as defined by groups <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J11/00</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J13/00</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J15/00</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J17/00</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J21/00</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J25/00</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J27/00</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J31/00</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J33/00</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J35/00</class-ref>, Ho1J37/00, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J40/00</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J41/00</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J47/00</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J49/00</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J61/00</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J63/00</class-ref> or <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J65/00</class-ref>, hereinafter called basic kinds. A detail only described with reference to, or clearly only applicable to, tubes or lamps of a single basic kind is classified in the detail group appropriate to tubes or lamps of that basic kind, e.g. <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J17/04</class-ref>.</note-paragraph></subnote> </note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>In this subclass, the following term is used with the meaning indicated: <pre>
						<br/>- &quot;lamp&quot; includes tubes emitting ultra-violet or infra-red <br/>  light.</pre> </note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>Attention is drawn to the definition of the expression &quot;spark gaps&quot; given in the Note following the title of subclass <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01T</class-ref>.</note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>Apparatus or processes specially adapted for the manufacture of electric discharge tubes, discharge lamps, or parts thereof are classified in group <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J9/00</class-ref>.</note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H01K.xml" sort-key="H01K" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H01K</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">ELECTRIC INCANDESCENT LAMPS </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">details or apparatus or processes for manufacture applicable to both discharge devices and incandescent lamps <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J</class-ref>; light sources using a combination of incandescent and other types of light generation <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J61/96</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H05B35/00</class-ref>; circuits therefor <class-ref scheme="cpc">H05B</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>In this subclass, the following term is used with the meaning indicated: <pre>
						<br/>- &quot;lamp&quot; includes tubes emitting ultra-violet or infra-red light.</pre> </note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H01L.xml" sort-key="H01L" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H01L</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">SEMICONDUCTOR DEVICES</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> ELECTRIC SOLID STATE DEVICES NOT OTHERWISE PROVIDED FOR </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">use of semiconductor devices for measuring <class-ref scheme="cpc">G01</class-ref>; resistors in general <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01C</class-ref>; magnets, inductors </text><CPC-specific-text><text scheme="cpc"> in general</text></CPC-specific-text><text scheme="ipc">, transformers <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01F</class-ref>; capacitors in general <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01G</class-ref>; electrolytic devices <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01G9/00</class-ref>; batteries, accumulators <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01M</class-ref>; waveguides, resonators or lines of the waveguide type <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01P</class-ref>; line connectors, current collectors <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01R</class-ref>; stimulated emission devices <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01S</class-ref>; electromechanical resonators <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03H</class-ref>; loudspeakers, microphones, gramophone pick-ups or like acoustic electromechanical transducers <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04R</class-ref>; electric light sources in general <class-ref scheme="cpc">H05B</class-ref>; printed circuits, hybrid circuits, casings or constructional details of electric apparatus, manufacture of assemblages of electrical components <class-ref scheme="cpc">H05K</class-ref>; use of semiconductor devices in circuits having a particular application, see the subclass for the application</text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass covers electric solid state devices which are not provided for in any other subclass and details thereof. This includes: <pre>- semiconductor devices adapted for rectifying, amplifying, oscillating or switching;<br/>- semiconductor devices sensitive to radiation;<br/>- electric solid state devices using thermoelectric,<br/>  superconductive, piezo-electric, electrostrictive,<br/>  magnetostrictive, galvano-magnetic or bulk negative<br/>  resistance effects and integrated circuit devices.</pre> Also covered by this subclass are photo-resistors, magnetic field dependent resistors, field effect resistors, capacitors with potential-jump barrier, resistors with potential-jump barrier or surface barrier, incoherent light emitting diodes, electromechanical solid state transducers and thin-film or thick-film circuits. Furthermore, it provides for processes and apparatus adapted for the manufacture or treatment of such devices, except where such processes relate to single step processes for which provision exists elsewhere.</note-paragraph><note-paragraph>In this subclass:<br/> The expression &quot;solid state body&quot; refers to the body of material within which, or at the surface of which, the physical effects characteristic of the device occur. In thermoelectric devices it includes all materials in the current path.<br/> Regions in or on the body of the device (other than the solid state body itself), which exert an influence on the solid state body electrically, are considered to be &quot;electrodes&quot; whether or not an external electrical connection is made thereto. <CPC-specific-text> Electrodes are often referred to as &quot;contacts&quot; in the literature.</CPC-specific-text> An electrode may include several portions and the term includes metallic regions which exert influence on the solid state body through an insulating region, (e.g. capacitive coupling) and inductive coupling arrangements to the body. The dielectric region in a capacitive arrangement is regarded as part of the electrode. In arrangements including several portions only those portions which exert an influence on the solid state body by virtue of their shape, size or disposition or the material of which they are formed are considered to be part of the electrode. The other portions are considered to be &quot;arrangements for conducting electric current to or from the solid state body&quot; or &quot;interconnections between solid state components formed in or on a common substrate&quot;, i.e. leads.<br/>The word &quot;device&quot; refers to an electric circuit element; where an electric circuit element is one of a plurality or elements formed in or on a common substrate it is referred to as a &quot;component&quot;.<br/>A &quot;complete device&quot; is a device in its fully assembled state which may or may not require further treatment, e.g. electro-forming, before it is ready for use but which does not require the addition of further structural units.<br/>The word &quot;parts&quot; includes all structural units which are included in a complete device.<br/>A &quot;container&quot; is an enclosure forming part of the complete device and is essentially a solid construction in which the body of the device is placed, or which is formed around the body without forming an intimate layer thereon. An enclosure which consists of one or more layers formed on the body and in intimate contact therewith is referred to as an &quot;encapsulation&quot;.<br/>&quot;Integrated circuit&quot; is a device where all components, e.g. diodes, resistors, are built up on a common substrate and form the device including interconnections between the components.</note-paragraph><note-paragraph>&quot;Integration processes&quot; are processes for the manufacture of at least two different components where the process is especially adapted to their integration, e.g. to take advantage of it or to reduce their manufacturing cost.<br/>Example: in a CMOS process, the same ion implant dopes the p-MOS gate and the n-MNOS source and drain. <br/>Consequently, a process for the manufacture of a component per se is not considered as an integration process, even though that component will be part of an integrated circuit.<br/>&quot;Assembly&quot; of a device is the building up of the device from its component constructional units and includes the provision of fillings in containers. <br/>When referring to the periodic table of the elements, either the new IUPAC notation, i.e. numbering system from 1 to 18, or the previous IUPAC form may be used to indicate an element group, e.g. group IV elements according to the previous IUPAC form correspond to group 14 elements according to the new notation</note-paragraph></note><note type="warning"> <note-paragraph> The following IPC groups are not used in the CPC scheme. Subject matter covered by these groups is classified in the following CPC groups <br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L21/301</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L21/30</class-ref><br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L21/328</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L29/66075</class-ref> <class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L21/329</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L29/66083</class-ref> <class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L21/33</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L29/66227</class-ref> <class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L21/331</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L29/66234</class-ref> <class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L21/332</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L29/66363</class-ref> <class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L21/334</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L29/66075</class-ref> <class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L21/335</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L29/66409</class-ref> <class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L21/336</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L29/66477</class-ref> <class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L21/337</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L29/66893</class-ref> <class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L21/338</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L29/66848</class-ref> <class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L21/339</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L29/66946</class-ref> <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L21/58</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L24/80</class-ref><br/><class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L21/8239</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="not-mapped">H01L27/105M</class-ref> <class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L21/60</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L24/80</class-ref><br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L21/66</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L22/34</class-ref> <class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L21/603</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L24/80</class-ref><br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L21/607</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L24/80</class-ref> <br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L21/8242</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L27/10844</class-ref><br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L21/8244</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L27/11</class-ref> <class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L21/8246</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L27/112</class-ref> <class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L21/8247</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L27/11517</class-ref> <class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L21/98</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L25/50</class-ref><br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L29/38</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L29/04</class-ref> to <class-ref scheme="not-mapped">H01L29/36D</class-ref><br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L29/96</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L29/68</class-ref> to <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L29/945</class-ref> <class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L51/30</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L51/0032</class-ref><br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L51/40</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="not-mapped">H01L51/00A</class-ref><br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L51/46</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L51/0032</class-ref><br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L51/48</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="not-mapped">H01L51/00A</class-ref><br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L51/54</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L51/0032</class-ref><br/></note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>Groups <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L23/562</class-ref> to <class-ref scheme="not-mapped">H01L23/576</class-ref> do not correspond to former or current IPC groups. Concordance CPC : IPC for these groups is as follows: - <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L23/562</class-ref> - <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L23/564</class-ref> : <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L23/00</class-ref> - <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L23/57</class-ref> : <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L23/58</class-ref></note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>Groups <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L22/00</class-ref> to <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L22/34</class-ref> do not correspond to a former or current IPC group. Concordance CPC : IPC for these groups is as follows: - <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L22/00</class-ref> - <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L22/34</class-ref> : <class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L21/66</class-ref></note-paragraph><note-paragraph>Groups <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L24/00</class-ref> to <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L24/98</class-ref> do not correspond to former or current IPC groups. Concordance CPC : IPC for these groups is as follows: - <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L24/00</class-ref> - <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L24/98</class-ref> : <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L23/00</class-ref></note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>Group <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L25/50</class-ref> does not correspond to a former or current IPC group. Concordance CPC : IPC for this group is as follows: - <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L25/50</class-ref> : <class-ref scheme="ipc">H01L21/98</class-ref></note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>Groups <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L28/00</class-ref> - <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L28/92</class-ref> do not correspond to former or current IPC groups. Concordance CPC : IPC for these groups is as follows: - <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L28/00</class-ref> - <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L28/92</class-ref> : <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L49/02</class-ref></note-paragraph> </note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H01M.xml" sort-key="H01M" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H01M</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">PROCESSES OR MEANS, e.g. BATTERIES, FOR THE DIRECT CONVERSION OF CHEMICAL INTO ELECTRICAL ENERGY </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">electrochemical processes or apparatus in general <class-ref scheme="cpc">C25</class-ref>; semiconductor or other solid state devices for converting light or heat into electrical energy <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L</class-ref>, e.g. <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L31/00</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L35/00</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L37/00</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass covers galvanic primary or secondary cells or batteries, fuel cells or batteries.</note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H01P.xml" sort-key="H01P" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H01P</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">WAVEGUIDES</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> RESONATORS, LINES, OR OTHER DEVICES OF THE WAVEGUIDE TYPE </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">operating at optical frequencies <class-ref scheme="cpc">G02B</class-ref>; aerials <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01Q</class-ref>; </text><CPC-specific-text><text scheme="cpc">modulating electromagnetic waves in transmission line, waveguide, cavity resonator or radiation field of aerial <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03C7/02</class-ref></text></CPC-specific-text><text scheme="ipc">; networks comprising lumped impedance elements <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03H</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>In this subclass, the following expression is used with the meaning indicated : <pre>
						<br/>- &quot;waveguide type&quot; as applied to transmission lines includes <br/>  only high-frequency coaxial cables or Lecher lines, and as <br/>  applied to resonators, delay lines, or other devices includes <br/>  all devices having distributed inductance and capacitance.</pre> </note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H01Q.xml" sort-key="H01Q" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H01Q</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">AERIALS </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">microwave radiators for near-field therepeutic treatment <class-ref scheme="cpc">A61N5/04</class-ref>; apparatus for testing aerials or for measuring aerial characteristics <class-ref scheme="cpc">G01R</class-ref>; waveguides <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01P</class-ref>; radiators or aerials for microwave heating <class-ref scheme="cpc">H05B6/72</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass covers: <pre>
						<br/>- in addition to the primary active radiating elements, <br/>  a) secondary devices for absorbing or for modifying the <br/>     direction or polarisation of waves radiated from aerials, <br/>     and <br/>  b) combinations with auxiliary devices such as earthing <br/>     switches, lead-in devices, and lightning protectors; <br/>- both transmitting and receiving aerials</pre> </note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>This subclass does not cover devices of the waveguide type, such as resonators or lines, not designed as radiating elements, which are covered by subclass <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01P</class-ref>.</note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>In this subclass, the following expression is used with the meaning indicated: <pre>
						<br/>- &quot;active radiating element&quot; covers corresponding parts of a <br/>  receiving aerial.</pre> </note-paragraph></note><note type="warning"> <note-paragraph> The following IPC groups are not used in the CPC scheme. Subject matter covered by these groups is classified in the following CPC groups : - <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01Q5/01</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01Q5/0003</class-ref> to <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01Q5/0096</class-ref> - <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01Q5/02</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01Q5/0003</class-ref> to <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01Q5/0096</class-ref>] </note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H01R.xml" sort-key="H01R" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H01R</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">LINE CONNECTORS</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> CURRENT COLLECTORS </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">switches, fuses <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H</class-ref>; coupling devices of the waveguide type <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01P5/00</class-ref>; switching arrangements for the supply or distribution of electric power <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02B</class-ref>; installations of electric lines, cables or auxiliary apparatus <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02G</class-ref>; printed means for providing electric connections to or between printed circuits <class-ref scheme="cpc">H05K</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass covers:<pre>
- all kinds of contact-making disconnectible and non-disconnectible electric line connectors, coupling devices, lamp or similar holders or current collectors for all kinds of electric lines, cables or apparatus;<br/>- non-printed means for electric connections to or between printed circuits.</pre></note-paragraph><note-paragraph>This subclass does not cover mounting of connections in or specified apparatus. Such mounting is covered by the relevant subclass for such apparatus, e.g. mounting in junction or distribution boxes is covered by subclass <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02B</class-ref> or <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02G</class-ref>, high-temperature connections for heating elements is covered by group <class-ref scheme="cpc">H05B3/08</class-ref>. Structural association of one part of a two-part coupling device with specific electric apparatus is classified with the apparatus e.g. association of cap with incandescent lamp is covered by subclass <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01K</class-ref>.</note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>In this subclass, a contact in a coupling device is only regarded as an additional earth contact if this contact is clearly designed for that purpose.</note-paragraph><note-paragraph>General details are classified in groups <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01R4/00</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01R9/00</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01R11/00</class-ref>.</note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H01S.xml" sort-key="H01S" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H01S</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">DEVICES USING STIMULATED EMISSION</text></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass covers: <subnote><note-paragraph>devices for the generation or amplification, by using stimulated emission, of coherent electromagnetic waves or other forms of wave energy; </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>such functions as modulating, demodulating, controlling, or stabilising such waves.</note-paragraph></subnote></note-paragraph></note><note type="warning"> <note-paragraph> The following IPC groups are not used in the CPC scheme.<br/> Subject matter covered by these groups is classified in the following CPC groups: <br/>- <class-ref scheme="ipc">H01S3/098</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="not-mapped">H01S3/08M</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01S3/11</class-ref> and s.gr.<br/></note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H01T.xml" sort-key="H01T" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H01T</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">SPARK GAPS</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> OVERVOLTAGE ARRESTERS USING SPARK GAPS</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> SPARKING PLUGS</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> CORONA DEVICES</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> GENERATING IONS TO BE INTRODUCED INTO NON-ENCLOSED GASES </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">working of metal by the action of a high concentration of electric current <class-ref scheme="cpc">B23H</class-ref>; welding, e.g. arc welding, electron beam welding or electrolytic welding <class-ref scheme="cpc">B23K</class-ref>; gas-filled discharge tubes with solid cathode <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J17/00</class-ref>; electric arc lamps <class-ref scheme="cpc">H05B31/00</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>In this subclass, the term &quot;spark gaps&quot; is used with the following meaning: <pre>
						<br/>- enclosed or non-enclosed discharge device having cold electrodes and used exclusively to discharge a quantity of electrical energy in a small time duration.</pre> </note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> </classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="4" additional-only="false" sort-key="H02" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H02</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">GENERATION</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> CONVERSION OR DISTRIBUTION OF ELECTRIC POWER</text></title-part></class-title> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H02B.xml" sort-key="H02B" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H02B</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">BOARDS, SUBSTATIONS, OR SWITCHING ARRANGEMENTS FOR THE SUPPLY OR DISTRIBUTION OF ELECTRIC POWER </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">basic electric elements, their assembly, including the mounting in enclosures or on bases, or the mounting of covers thereon, see the subclasses for such elements, e.g. transformers <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01F</class-ref>, switches, fuses <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H</class-ref>, line connectors <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01R</class-ref>; installation of lines, cables, or other conductors for supply or distribution <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02G</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass covers boards, switchyards, switchgear or their installation, or the association of switching devices with each other or with other devices, e.g. transformers, fuses, meters or distribution boards; such associations constitute substations or distribution points.</note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H02G.xml" sort-key="H02G" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H02G</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">INSTALLATION OF ELECTRIC CABLES OR LINES, OR OF COMBINED OPTICAL AND ELECTRIC CABLES OR LINES </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">distribution points incorporating switches <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02B</class-ref>; guiding telephone cords <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04M1/15</class-ref>; cable ducts or mountings for telephone or telegraph exchange installations <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04Q1/06</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph><br/>1. This subclass covers installation of communication cables or lines, including those comprising a combination of optical and electrical conductors, or of lightning conductors as well as installation of power cables or lines.</note-paragraph> <note-paragraph><br/>2. This subclass does not cover installation of purely optical cables, which is covered by groups <CPC-specific-text> <class-ref scheme="not-mapped">G02B6/44C</class-ref></CPC-specific-text>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">G02B6/46</class-ref>.</note-paragraph> <note-paragraph><br/>3. In this subclass, the following expression is used with the meaning indicated: <pre>
						<br/>- &quot;electric cable&quot; includes cables comprising optical <br/>  conductors, e.g. fibres, in combination with electrical <br/>  conductors.</pre> </note-paragraph><note-paragraph> <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02G2200/00</class-ref> whenever appropriate </note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H02H.xml" sort-key="H02H" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H02H</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">EMERGENCY PROTECTIVE CIRCUIT ARRANGEMENTS </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">indicating or signalling undesired working conditions <class-ref scheme="cpc">G01R</class-ref>, e.g. <class-ref scheme="cpc">G01R31/00</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">G08B</class-ref>; locating faults along lines <class-ref scheme="cpc">G01R31/08</class-ref>; emergency protective devices <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass covers only circuit arrangements for the automatic protection of electric lines or electric machines or apparatus in the event of an undesired change from normal working conditions</note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H02J.xml" sort-key="H02J" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H02J</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">CIRCUIT ARRANGEMENTS OR SYSTEMS FOR SUPPLYING OR DISTRIBUTING ELECTRIC POWER</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> SYSTEMS FOR STORING ELECTRIC ENERGY </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">for digital computers <class-ref scheme="cpc">G06F1/18</class-ref>; circuits or apparatus for the conversion of electric power, arrangements for control or regulation of such circuits or apparatus <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02M</class-ref>; interrelated control of several motors, control of a prime-mover/generator combination <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02P</class-ref>; control of high-frequency power <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03L</class-ref>; additional use of power line or power network for transmission of information <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04B</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass covers: <pre>
						<br/>- ac or dc mains or distribution networks; <br/>- circuit arrangements for battery supplies, including <br/>  charging or control thereof, or co-ordinated supply <br/>  from two or more sources of any kind; <br/>- systems for supplying or distributing electric power <br/>  by electromagnetic waves.</pre> </note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>This subclass does not cover: <pre>
						<br/>- control of a single motor, generator or dynamo-electric <br/>  converter, of the types covered by subclass <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01F</class-ref> or <br/>  <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02K</class-ref>, which is covered by subclass <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02P</class-ref>; <br/>- control of a single motor or generator, of the types <br/>  covered by subclass <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02N</class-ref>, which is covered by that <br/>  subclass.</pre> </note-paragraph></note><note type="warning"><note-paragraph> <subnote><note-paragraph>The following IPC groups are not used in the CPC scheme. Subject matter covered by these groups is classified in the following CPC groups : <pre>
								<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H02J7/10</class-ref>     covered by    <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02J7/0072</class-ref></pre> </note-paragraph></subnote></note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H02K.xml" sort-key="H02K" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H02K</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">DYNAMO-ELECTRIC MACHINES </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">measuring instruments <class-ref scheme="cpc">G01</class-ref>; dynamo-electric relays <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H53/00</class-ref>; conversion of dc or ac input power into surge output power </text><CPC-specific-text><text scheme="cpc"> <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03K3/53</class-ref></text></CPC-specific-text><text scheme="ipc">; loudspeakers, microphones, gramophone pick-ups or like acoustic electromechanical transducers <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04R</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass covers structural adaptation of the machine for the purposes of its control.</note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>This subclass does not cover starting, regulating, electronically commutating, braking, or otherwise controlling motors, generators or dynamo-electric converters, in general, which are covered by subclass <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02P</class-ref>.</note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H02M.xml" sort-key="H02M" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H02M</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">APPARATUS FOR CONVERSION BETWEEN AC AND AC, BETWEEN AC AND DC, OR BETWEEN DC AND DC, AND FOR USE WITH MAINS OR SIMILAR POWER SUPPLY SYSTEMS</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> CONVERSION OF DC OR AC INPUT POWER INTO SURGE OUTPUT POWER</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> CONTROL OR REGULATION THEREOF </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">systems for regulating electric or magnetic variables in general, e.g. using transformers, reactors or choke coils, combination of such systems with static converters <class-ref scheme="cpc">G05F</class-ref>; </text><CPC-specific-text><text scheme="cpc"> digital function or clock generators</text></CPC-specific-text><text scheme="ipc"> for digital computers <class-ref scheme="cpc">G06F1/00</class-ref>, </text><CPC-specific-text><text scheme="cpc"> <class-ref scheme="cpc">G06F1/025</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">G06F1/04</class-ref></text></CPC-specific-text><text scheme="ipc">; transformers <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01F</class-ref>; connection or control of one converter with regard to conjoint operation with a similar or other source of supply <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02J</class-ref>; dynamo-electric converters <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02K47/00</class-ref>; controlling transformers, reactors or choke coils, control or regulation of electric motors, generators or dynamo-electric converters <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02P</class-ref>; pulse generators <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03K</class-ref>; </text><CPC-specific-text><text scheme="cpc"> static converters specially adapted for igniting or operating discharge lamps <class-ref scheme="cpc">H05B41/28</class-ref></text></CPC-specific-text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass covers only circuits or apparatus for the conversion of electric power, or arrangements for control or regulation of such circuits or apparatus. The electrotechnical elements employed are dealt within the appropriate subclasses, e.g. inductors, transformers <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01F</class-ref>, capacitors, electrolytic rectifiers <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01G</class-ref>, mercury rectifying or other discharge tubes <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J</class-ref>, semiconductor devices <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L</class-ref>, impedance networks or resonant circuit not primarily concerned with the transfer of electric power <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03H</class-ref>.</note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>In this subclass, the following term is used with the meaning indicated: <pre>- &quot;conversion&quot;, in respect of an electric variable, e.g. voltage or current, means the change of one or more of the parameters of the variable, e.g. amplitude, frequency, phase, polarity.</pre> </note-paragraph></note><note type="warning"> <note-paragraph><br/>The following IPC groups are not used in the CPC scheme. Subject matter covered by these groups is classified in the following CPC groups : <pre>
						<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H02M9/00</class-ref> covered by  <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03K3/53</class-ref>
						<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H02M9/02</class-ref> covered by  <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03K3/53</class-ref>
						<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H02M9/04</class-ref> covered by  <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03K3/53</class-ref>
						<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H02M9/06</class-ref> covered by  <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03K3/53</class-ref>
					</pre> </note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H02N.xml" sort-key="H02N" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H02N</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">ELECTRIC MACHINES NOT OTHERWISE PROVIDED FOR</text></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass covers: <pre>
						<br/>- electrostatic generators, motors, clutches, or holding <br/>  devices; <br/>- other non-dynamo-electric generators or motors; <br/>- holding or levitation devices using magnetic attraction <br/>  or repulsion; <br/>- arrangements for starting, regulating, braking, or otherwise <br/>  controlling such machines unless in conjoint operation with <br/>  a second machine.</pre> </note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>Specific provision for generators, motors, or other means for converting between electric and other forms of energy also exists in other subclasses, e.g. in subclasses <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01M</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02K</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04R</class-ref>.</note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H02P.xml" sort-key="H02P" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H02P</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">CONTROL OR REGULATION OF ELECTRIC MOTORS, GENERATORS, OR DYNAMO-ELECTRIC CONVERTERS</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> CONTROLLING TRANSFORMERS, REACTORS OR CHOKE COILS </text><reference><CPC-specific-text><text scheme="cpc"> specially adapted for electrically propelled vehicles <class-ref scheme="cpc">B60L</class-ref></text></CPC-specific-text><text scheme="ipc">; structure of the starter, brake, or other control devices, see the relevant subclasses, e.g. mechanical brake <class-ref scheme="cpc">F16D</class-ref>, mechanical speed regulator <class-ref scheme="cpc">G05D</class-ref>, variable resistor <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01C</class-ref>, starter switch <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H</class-ref>; systems for regulating electric or magnetic variables using transformers, reactors or choke coils <class-ref scheme="cpc">G05F</class-ref>; arrangements structurally associated with motors, generators, dynamo-electric converters, transformers, reactors or choke coils, see the relevant subclasses, e.g. <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01F</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02K</class-ref>; connection or control of one generator, transformer, reactor, choke coil, or dynamo-electric converter with regard to conjoint operation with similar or other source of supply <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02J</class-ref>; control or regulation of static converters <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02M</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass covers arrangements for starting, regulating, electronically commutating, braking, or otherwise controlling motors, generators, dynamo-electric converters, clutches, brakes, gears, transformers, reactors or choke coils, of the types classified in the relevant subclasses, e.g. <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01F</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02K</class-ref>.</note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>This subclass does not cover similar arrangements for the apparatus of the types classified in subclass <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02N</class-ref>, which arrangements are covered by that subclass.</note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>In this subclass, the following terms or expressions are used with the meanings indicated:<br/><pre>
- &quot;control&quot; means influencing a variable in any way, e.g. changing its direction or its value (including changing it to or from zero), maintaining it constant, limiting its range of variation; <br/>- &quot;regulation&quot; means maintaining a variable at a desired value, or within a desired range of values, by comparison of the actual value with the desired value.</pre></note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H02S.xml" sort-key="H02S" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H02S</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">GENERATION OF ELECTRIC POWER BY CONVERSION OF INFRA-RED RADIATION, VISIBLE LIGHT OR ULTRAVIOLET LIGHT, e.g. USING PHOTOVOLTAIC [PV] MODULES </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">light sensitive inorganic semiconductor devices <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L31/00</class-ref>; thermoelectric devices <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L35/00</class-ref>; pyroelectric devices <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L37/00</class-ref>; light sensitive organic semiconductor devices <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L51/00</class-ref>; obtaining electrical energy from radioactive sources <class-ref scheme="cpc">G21H1/12</class-ref>; solar heat collectors <class-ref scheme="cpc">F24J2/00</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="warning"> <note-paragraph>Subclass <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02S</class-ref> corresponds to IPC2014.01. Concordance CPC : IPC for the groups is as follows: - <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02S10/00</class-ref> : <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L31/04</class-ref> - <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02S20/00</class-ref> : <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L31/042</class-ref> - <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02S30/00</class-ref> : <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L31/042</class-ref> - <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02S40/00</class-ref> : <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L31/042</class-ref> - <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02S50/00</class-ref> : <class-ref scheme="cpc">G01R31/40</class-ref> - <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02S99/00</class-ref> : <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02N6/00</class-ref> ] </note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> </classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="4" additional-only="false" sort-key="H03" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H03</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">BASIC ELECTRONIC CIRCUITRY</text></title-part></class-title> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H03B.xml" sort-key="H03B" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H03B</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">GENERATION OF OSCILLATIONS, DIRECTLY OR BY FREQUENCY-CHANGING, BY CIRCUITS EMPLOYING ACTIVE ELEMENTS WHICH OPERATE IN A NON-SWITCHING MANNER</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> GENERATION OF NOISE BY SUCH CIRCUITS </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">measuring, testing <class-ref scheme="cpc">G01R</class-ref>; generators adapted for electrophonic musical instruments <class-ref scheme="cpc">G10H</class-ref>; Speech synthesis <class-ref scheme="cpc">G10L</class-ref>; masers, lasers <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01S</class-ref>; dynamo-electric machines <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02K</class-ref>; power inverter circuits <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02M</class-ref>; by using pulse techniques <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03K</class-ref>; automatic control of generators <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03L</class-ref>; starting, synchronisation or stabilisation of generators where the type of generator is irrelevant or unspecified <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03L</class-ref>; generation of oscillations in plasma <class-ref scheme="cpc">H05H</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H03C.xml" sort-key="H03C" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H03C</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">MODULATION </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">measuring, testing <class-ref scheme="cpc">G01R</class-ref>; masers, lasers <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01S</class-ref>; modulators specially adapted for use in the amplifiers <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03F3/38</class-ref>; modulating pulses <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03K7/00</class-ref>; so-called modulators capable only of a switching between predetermined states of amplitude, frequency or phase <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03K17/00</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04L</class-ref>; coding, decoding or code conversion, in general <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03M</class-ref>; synchronous modulators specially adapted for colour television <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04N9/65</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass <u>covers</u> only modulation, keying, or interruption of sinusoidal oscillations or electromagnetic waves, the modulating signal having any desired waveform.</note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>In this subclass, circuits usable both as modulator and demodulator are classified in the group dealing with the type of modulator involved.</note-paragraph></note><note type="warning"><note-paragraph>The following IPC groups are not used in the CPC scheme. Subject matter covered by these groups is classified in the following CPC groups : <pre>
						<class-ref scheme="ipc">H03C1/38</class-ref> to <class-ref scheme="ipc">H03C1/44</class-ref>    covered by    <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03C1/36</class-ref>
					</pre> </note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H03D.xml" sort-key="H03D" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H03D</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">DEMODULATION OR TRANSFERENCE OF MODULATION FROM ONE CARRIER TO ANOTHER </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">masers, lasers <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01S</class-ref>; circuits capable of acting both as modulator and demodulator <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03C</class-ref>; details applicable to both modulators and frequency-changers <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03C</class-ref>; demodulating pulses <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03K9/00</class-ref>; transforming types of pulse modulation <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03K11/00</class-ref>; coding, decoding or code conversion, in general <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03M</class-ref>; repeater stations <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04B7/14</class-ref>; demodulators adapted for ac systems of digital information transmission <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04L27/00</class-ref>; synchronous demodulators adapted for colour television <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04N9/66</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass covers only: <pre>
						<br/>- demodulation or transference of signals modulated on a <br/>  sinusoidal carrier or on electromagnetic waves; <br/>- comparing phase or frequency of two mutually-independent <br/>  oscillations.</pre> </note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H03F.xml" sort-key="H03F" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H03F</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">AMPLIFIERS </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">measuring, testing <class-ref scheme="cpc">G01R</class-ref>; optical parametric amplifiers <class-ref scheme="cpc">G02F</class-ref>; circuit arrangement with secondary emission tubes <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J43/30</class-ref>; masers, lasers <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01S</class-ref>; control of amplification <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03G</class-ref>; coupling arrangements independent of the nature of the amplifiers, voltage dividers <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03H</class-ref>; amplifiers capable only of dealing with pulses <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03K</class-ref>; repeater circuits in transmission lines <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04B3/36</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04B3/58</class-ref>; application of speech amplifiers in telephonic communication <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04M1/60</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04M3/40</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass covers: <pre>
						<br/>- linear amplification, there being linear relationship between <br/>  the amplitudes of input and output, and the output having <br/>  substantially the same waveform as the input; <br/>- dielectric amplifiers, magnetic amplifiers, and parametric <br/>  amplifiers when used as oscillators or frequency-changers; <br/>- constructions of active elements of dielectric amplifiers <br/>  and parametric amplifiers if no provision exists elsewhere.</pre> </note-paragraph></note><note type="warning"><note-paragraph><subnote><note-paragraph>The following IPC groups are not used in the CPC scheme. Subject matter covered by these groups is classified in the following CPC groups: <pre>
								<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H03F1/44</class-ref>    covered by    <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03F1/42</class-ref>
								<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H03F1/46</class-ref>    covered by    <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03F1/42</class-ref>
								<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H03F3/18</class-ref>    covered by    <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03F3/00</class-ref>
								<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H03F3/32</class-ref>    covered by    <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03F3/30</class-ref>
								<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H03F7/06</class-ref>    covered by    <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03F7/00</class-ref></pre> </note-paragraph></subnote></note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H03G.xml" sort-key="H03G" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H03G</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">CONTROL OF AMPLIFICATION </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">impedance networks, e.g. attenuators, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03H</class-ref>; control of transmission in lines <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04B3/04</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass covers: <pre>
						<br/>- control of gain of amplifiers or frequency-changers, <br/>- control of frequency range of amplifiers, <br/>- limiting amplitude or rate of change of amplitude</pre> </note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>Attention is drawn to the Note following the title of subclass <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03F</class-ref>.</note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H03H.xml" sort-key="H03H" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H03H</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">IMPEDANCE NETWORKS, e.g. RESONANT CIRCUITS</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> RESONATORS </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">measuring, testing <class-ref scheme="cpc">G01R</class-ref>; arrangements for producing a reverberation or echo sound <class-ref scheme="cpc">G10K15/08</class-ref>; impedance networks or resonators consisting of distributed impedances, e.g. of the waveguide type, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01P</class-ref>; control of amplification, e.g. bandwidth control of amplifiers, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03G</class-ref>; tuning resonant circuits, e.g. tuning coupled resonant circuits, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03J</class-ref>; networks for modifying the frequency characteristics of communication systems <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04B</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"> <note-paragraph>This subclass <u>covers</u>: <subnote><note-paragraph>networks comprising lumped impedance elements;</note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>networks comprising distributed impedance elements together with lumped impedance elements;</note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>networks comprising electromechanical or electro-acoustic elements;</note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>networks simulating reactances and comprising discharge tubes or semiconductor devices;</note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>constructions of electromechanical resonators.</note-paragraph></subnote></note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>In this subclass, the following expression is used with the meaning indicated: <subnote><note-paragraph>&quot;passive elements&quot; means resistors, capacitors, inductors, mutual inductors or diodes.</note-paragraph></subnote></note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>Attention is drawn to the Notes following the titles of class <class-ref scheme="cpc">B81</class-ref> and subclass <class-ref scheme="cpc">B81B</class-ref> relating to &quot;micro-structural devices&quot; and &quot;micro-structural systems&quot;.</note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>In this subclass, main groups with a higher number take precedence.</note-paragraph> </note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H03J.xml" sort-key="H03J" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H03J</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">TUNING RESONANT CIRCUITS</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> SELECTING RESONANT CIRCUITS </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">indicating arrangements for measuring <class-ref scheme="cpc">G01D</class-ref>; measuring, testing <class-ref scheme="cpc">G01R</class-ref>; remote-control in general <class-ref scheme="cpc">G05</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">G08</class-ref>; automatic control or stabilisation of generators <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03L</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass covers also the control of tuning, including the combined control of tuning and other functions, e.g. combinations of tuning control and volume control, combinations of control of local oscillator and of supplementary resonant circuits.</note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H03K.xml" sort-key="H03K" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H03K</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">PULSE TECHNIQUE </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">measuring pulse characteristics <class-ref scheme="cpc">G01R</class-ref>; mechanical counters having an electrical input <class-ref scheme="cpc">G06M</class-ref>; information storage devices in general <class-ref scheme="cpc">G11</class-ref>; sample-and-hold arrangements in electric analogue stores <class-ref scheme="cpc">G11C27/02</class-ref>; construction of switches involving contact making and breaking for generation of pulses, e.g. by using a moving magnet, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H</class-ref>; static conversion of electric power <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02M</class-ref>; generation of oscillations by circuits employing active elements which operate in a non-switching manner <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03B</class-ref>; modulating sinusoidal oscillations with pulses <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03C</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04L</class-ref>; discriminator circuits involving pulse counting <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03D</class-ref>; automatic control of generators <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03L</class-ref>; starting, synchronisation or stabilisation of generators where the type of generator is irrelevant or unspecified <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03L</class-ref>; coding, decoding or code conversion in general <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03M</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass covers: <pre>
						<br/>- methods, circuits, devices, or apparatus using active <br/>  elements operating in a discontinuous or switching manner <br/>  for generating, counting, amplifying, shaping, modulating, <br/>  demodulating, or otherwise manipulating signals; <br/>- electronic switching not involving contact-making and <br/>  braking; <br/>- logic circuits handling electric pulses.</pre> </note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>In this subclass, the following expression is used with the meaning indicated: <pre>
						<br/>- &quot;active element&quot; exercises control over the conversion of <br/>  input energy into an oscillation or a discontinuous flow of <br/>  energy.</pre> </note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>In this subclass, where the claims of a patent document are not limited to a specific circuit element, the document is classified at least according to the elements used in the described embodiment.</note-paragraph></note><note type="warning"><note-paragraph>The following IPC groups are not used in the CPC scheme. Subject matter covered by these groups is classified in the following CPC groups : <pre>
						<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H03K17/695</class-ref>      covered by      <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03K17/687</class-ref></pre> </note-paragraph> </note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H03L.xml" sort-key="H03L" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H03L</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">AUTOMATIC CONTROL, STARTING, SYNCHRONISATION, OR STABILISATION OF GENERATORS OF ELECTRONIC OSCILLATIONS OR PULSES </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">of dynamo-electric generators <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02P</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass covers: <pre>
						<br/>- automatic control circuits for generators of electronic <br/>  oscillations or pulses; <br/>- starting, synchronisation, or stabilisation circuits for <br/>  generators where the type of generator is irrelevant or <br/>  unspecified.</pre> </note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>This subclass does not cover stabilisation or starting circuits specially adapted to only one specific type of generator, which are covered by subclasses <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03B</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03K</class-ref>.</note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>In this subclass, the following expression is used with the meaning indicated: <pre>
						<br/>- &quot;automatic control&quot; covers only closed loop systems.</pre> </note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H03M.xml" sort-key="H03M" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H03M</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">CODING</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> DECODING</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> CODE CONVERSION IN GENERAL </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">using fluidic means <class-ref scheme="cpc">F15C4/00</class-ref>; optical analogue/digital converters <class-ref scheme="cpc">G02F7/00</class-ref>; coding, decoding or code conversion, specially adapted for particular applications, see the relevant subclasses, e.g. <class-ref scheme="cpc">G01D</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">G01R</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">G06F</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">G06T</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">G09G</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">G10L</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">G11B</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">G11C</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04B</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04L</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04M</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04N</class-ref>; ciphering or deciphering for cryptography or other purposes involving the need for secrecy <class-ref scheme="cpc">G09C</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="warning"> <note-paragraph>The following IPC groups are not used in the CPC scheme. Subject matter covered by these groups is classified in the following CPC groups: <pre>
						<class-ref scheme="ipc">H03M7/32</class-ref>	covered by	<class-ref scheme="cpc">H03M7/3004</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03M7/3048</class-ref>
						<class-ref scheme="ipc">H03M7/34</class-ref>	covered by	<class-ref scheme="cpc">H03M7/3004</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03M7/3051</class-ref>
						<class-ref scheme="ipc">H03M7/36</class-ref>	covered by	<class-ref scheme="cpc">H03M7/3004</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03M7/3044</class-ref>
						<class-ref scheme="ipc">H03M7/38</class-ref>	covered by	<class-ref scheme="cpc">H03M7/3004</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03M7/3046</class-ref></pre> </note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> </classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="4" additional-only="false" sort-key="H04" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H04</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">ELECTRIC COMMUNICATION TECHNIQUE</text></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This class covers electrical communication systems with propagation paths employing light (optical communication), infra-red, ultrasonic, sonic, or infrasonic waves.</note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H04B.xml" sort-key="H04B" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H04B</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">TRANSMISSION </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">transmission systems for measured values, control or similar signals <class-ref scheme="cpc">G08C</class-ref>; coding, decoding, code conversion, in general <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03M</class-ref>; broadcast communication <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04H</class-ref>; multiplex systems <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04J</class-ref>; secret communication <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04K</class-ref>; transmission of digital information <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04L</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass covers the transmission of information-carrying signals, the transmission being independent of the nature of the information, and includes monitoring and testing arrangements and the suppression and limitation of noise and interference.</note-paragraph></note><note type="warning"> <note-paragraph> The following IPC groups are not used in the CPC scheme. Subject matter covered by these groups is classified in the following CPC groups:<pre>
						<class-ref scheme="ipc">H04B10/04</class-ref>    covered by   <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04B10/50</class-ref>
						<class-ref scheme="ipc">H04B10/06</class-ref>    covered by   <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04B10/60</class-ref>
						<class-ref scheme="ipc">H04B10/08</class-ref>    covered by   <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04B10/07</class-ref>
						<class-ref scheme="ipc">H04B10/10</class-ref>    covered by   <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04B10/11</class-ref>
						<class-ref scheme="ipc">H04B10/13</class-ref>    covered by   <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04B10/2581</class-ref>
						<class-ref scheme="ipc">H04B10/26</class-ref>    covered by   <class-ref scheme="not-mapped">H04B10/24B</class-ref>
						<class-ref scheme="ipc">H04B10/28</class-ref>    covered by   <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04B10/43</class-ref></pre> </note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H04H.xml" sort-key="H04H" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H04H</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">BROADCAST COMMUNICATION </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">multiplex communication <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04J</class-ref>; pictorial communication aspects of broadcast systems <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04N</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"> <note-paragraph><br/><pre>
1. In this subclass, the following terms or expressions are used with the meaning indicated:<br/>- &#8220;broadcast&#8221; is simultaneous distribution of identical signals to plural receiving stations. The term &quot;broadcast&quot; does not include distribution to&#160;receiving stations which is controlled by requests or responses from the receiving stations;<br/>- &#8220;broadcast information&#8221; covers all kinds of information distributed by broadcast systems;<br/>- &#8220;broadcast-related information&#8221; is information required by services provided via broadcast systems, other than broadcast information;<br/>- &#8220;broadcast time&#8221; is a time when particular broadcast information exists and is available;<br/>- &#8220;broadcast channel&#8221; is a channel via which broadcast information is distributed, e.g. carrier waves, time slots, cables or wireless broadcast service areas;<br/>- &#8220;broadcast space&#8221; is either a set of broadcast channels in which particular broadcast information exists and is available or a geographical area determined by the set of broadcast channels;<br/>- &#8220;broadcast space-time&#8221; is space-time determined by broadcast space and broadcast time in which particular broadcast information exists and is available;<br/>- &#8220;broadcast system&#8221; is a system which consists of transmitter, transponder and receiver for broadcast;<br/>- &#8220;broadcast-related system&#8221; is a system which is directly affected by generation, broadcast, reception or use of broadcast information;<br/>- &#8220;broadcast service&#8221; is a service directly provided by a broadcast system, i.e. distribution service of broadcast information;<br/>- &#8220;broadcast-related service&#8221; is a service provided by broadcast-related systems;<br/>- &#8220;A with a direct linkage to B&#8221; means that A directly affects B or that A is directly affected by B.<br/>
2. In this subclass, multi-aspect classification is applied, so that subject matter characterised by aspects covered by more than one of its groups, which is considered to represent information of interest for search, may also be classified in each of those groups.</pre></note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H04J.xml" sort-key="H04J" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H04J</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">MULTIPLEX COMMUNICATION </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">transmission in general <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04B</class-ref>; peculiar to transmission of digital information <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04L5/00</class-ref>; systems for the simultaneous or sequential transmission of more than one television signal <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04N7/08</class-ref>; in exchanges <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04Q11/00</class-ref>; stereophonic systems <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04S</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass covers<br/><pre>
- circuits or apparatus for combining or dividing signals for <br/>  the purpose of transmitting them simultaneously or sequentially over the same transmission path; <br/>- monitoring arrangements therefor.</pre> </note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H04K.xml" sort-key="H04K" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H04K</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">SECRET COMMUNICATION</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> JAMMING OF COMMUNICATION</text></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>In this subclass, the following expression is used with the meaning indicated: <pre>
- &quot;secret communication&quot; includes secret line and radiation transmission systems, i.e. those in which apparatus at the transmitting station modifies the signal in such a way that the information cannot be intelligibly received without corresponding modifying apparatus at the receiving station.</pre> </note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H04L.xml" sort-key="H04L" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H04L</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">TRANSMISSION OF DIGITAL INFORMATION, e.g. TELEGRAPHIC COMMUNICATION </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">typewriters <class-ref scheme="cpc">B41J</class-ref>; order telegraphs, fire or police telegraphs <class-ref scheme="cpc">G08B</class-ref>; visual telegraphy <class-ref scheme="cpc">G08B</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">G08C</class-ref>; teleautographic systems <class-ref scheme="cpc">G08C</class-ref>; ciphering or deciphering apparatus per se <class-ref scheme="cpc">G09C</class-ref>; coding, decoding or code conversion, in general <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03M</class-ref>; arrangements common to telegraphic and telephonic communication <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04M</class-ref>; selecting <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04Q</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass covers transmission of signals having been supplied in digital form and includes data transmission, telegraphic communication and methods or arrangements for monitoring.</note-paragraph></note><note type="warning"> <note-paragraph>The following IPC groups are not used in the CPC scheme. Subject matter covered by these groups is classified in the following CPC groups:<pre>
						<class-ref scheme="ipc">H04L12/20</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04L29/00</class-ref>
						<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H04L25/04</class-ref>          &quot;           <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04L25/03</class-ref>
						<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H04L25/17</class-ref>          &quot;           <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03H</class-ref> <br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H04L25/18</class-ref>          &quot;           <class-ref scheme="not-mapped">H04L25/02G1C</class-ref>
						<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H04L25/28</class-ref>          &quot;           <class-ref scheme="not-mapped">H04L25/02G1A</class-ref>
						<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H04L25/30</class-ref>          &quot;           <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04L25/061</class-ref>
						<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H04L25/32</class-ref>          &quot;           <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04L25/49</class-ref>
						<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H04L25/34</class-ref>          &quot;           <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04L25/4917</class-ref>
						<br/><class-ref scheme="not-mapped">H04L25/36</class-ref>          &quot;           <class-ref scheme="not-mapped">H04L25/02A</class-ref>
						<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H04L25/48</class-ref>          &quot;           <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04L25/49</class-ref>
						<br/><class-ref scheme="not-mapped">H04L25/50</class-ref>          &quot;           <class-ref scheme="not-mapped">H04L25/02A</class-ref>
						<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H04L25/52</class-ref>          &quot;           <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04L25/20</class-ref>
						<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H04L25/54</class-ref>          &quot;           <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04L25/20</class-ref>
						<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H04L25/56</class-ref>          &quot;           <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04L25/202</class-ref>
						<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H04L25/58</class-ref>          &quot;           <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04L25/20</class-ref>
						<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H04L25/60</class-ref>          &quot;           <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04L25/207</class-ref>
						<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H04L25/62</class-ref>          &quot;           <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04L25/205</class-ref>
						<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H04L25/64</class-ref>          &quot;           <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04L25/245</class-ref>
						<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H04L25/66</class-ref>          &quot;           <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04L25/247</class-ref></pre> </note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H04M.xml" sort-key="H04M" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H04M</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">TELEPHONIC COMMUNICATION </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">counting mechanisms <class-ref scheme="cpc">G06M</class-ref>; circuits for controlling other apparatus via a telephone cable and not involving telephone switching apparatus <class-ref scheme="cpc">G08</class-ref>; reels or other take-up devices for cords <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02G11/00</class-ref>; multiplex transmission between switching centres <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04J</class-ref>; selecting arrangements <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04Q</class-ref>; loudspeakers, microphones, gramophone pick-ups or like electromechanical transducers <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04R</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass covers : <pre>
						<br/>- telephonic communication systems combined with other <br/>  electrical systems; <br/>- testing arrangements peculiar to telephonic communication <br/>  systems.</pre> </note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>In this subclass, the following terms or expressions are used with the meanings indicated : <pre>
						<br/>- &quot;subscriber&quot; is a general term for terminal equipment, e.g. <br/>  telephone for public use; <br/>- &quot;substation&quot; means a subscriber or monitoring equipment <br/>  which may connect a single subscriber to a line without <br/>  choice as to subscriber; <br/>- &quot;satellite&quot; is a type of exchange the operation of which <br/>  depends upon control signals received from a supervisory <br/>  exchange; <br/>- &quot;switching centres&quot; includes exchanges and satellites.</pre> </note-paragraph></note><note type="warning"> <note-paragraph>The following IPC groups are not used in the CPC scheme. Subject matter covered by these groups are classified in the following CPC groups : <pre>
						<br/><class-ref scheme="cpc">H04M1/677</class-ref>  covered by  <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04M1/677</class-ref>
						<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H04M7/02</class-ref>  covered by  <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04Q3/00</class-ref>
						<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H04M7/04</class-ref>  covered by  <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04Q3/00</class-ref>
						<br/><class-ref scheme="ipc">H04M7/10</class-ref>  covered by  <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04Q3/00</class-ref>
						<br/></pre> </note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H04N.xml" sort-key="H04N" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H04N</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">PICTORIAL COMMUNICATION, e.g. TELEVISION </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">measuring, testing <class-ref scheme="cpc">G01</class-ref>; systems for autographic writing, e.g. writing telegraphy, which involve following an outline </text><CPC-specific-text><text scheme="cpc"> <class-ref scheme="cpc">G08C21/00</class-ref></text></CPC-specific-text><text scheme="ipc">; information storage based on relative movement between record carrier and transducer <class-ref scheme="cpc">G11B</class-ref>; coding, decoding or code conversion, in general <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03M</class-ref>; broadcast distribution or the recording of use made thereof <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04H</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>1. This subclass <u>covers</u>: <subnote><note-paragraph><CPC-specific-text> generation, recording or</CPC-specific-text> transmission of pictures or their transient or permanent reproduction either locally or remotely <CPC-specific-text> and the corresponding electronic image capture and reproduction process employing image representative electric signals,</CPC-specific-text> by methods or arrangements <CPC-specific-text> involving at least one of</CPC-specific-text> the following steps: <subnote><note-paragraph>step (a): the <CPC-specific-text> electronic acquisition or</CPC-specific-text> scanning of a picture <CPC-specific-text> or scene</CPC-specific-text>, i.e. resolving the whole picture-containing area into individual picture-elements and the derivation of picture-representative electric signals related thereto, simultaneously or in sequence <CPC-specific-text> , e.g. by reading an electronic solid-state image sensor [SSIS</CPC-specific-text> pickup device (e.g. CCD or CMOS image sensor) as electronic image sensor converting optical image information into said electrical signals;]</note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>step (b): the reproduction of the whole picture-containing area <CPC-specific-text> or scene</CPC-specific-text> by the reproduction of individual picture-elements into which the picture is resolved by means of picture representative electric signals derived therefrom, simultaneously or in sequence [N: by converting an electric image signal into light e.g. with an electronic spatial light modulator; </note-paragraph></subnote></note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>concerning cameras or projectors: <subnote><note-paragraph>video cameras or TV cameras, e.g. in studios, CCTV cameras, surveillance cameras, camcorders; constructional or mechanical details related to such cameras even when not peculiar to the presence of an electronic image sensor [EIS] e.g. housings; </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>arrangements or methods for image capture using an EIS or image projection using an electronic spatial light modulator [ESLM], i.e. <subnote><note-paragraph>(i) sensor read-out; </note-paragraph></subnote><subnote><note-paragraph>(ii) processing of electrical image signals from the EIS or provided to the ESLM for the generation of respective camera or projector control signals, <subnote><note-paragraph>for controlling the EIS or its read-out for e.g. exposure, scene selection for auto focussing, or electronic image enhancement or processing of the image signals captured by the EIS, e.g. white balance, electronic motion blur correction, noise suppression <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04N5/00</class-ref>,</note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>for controlling the ESLM, e.g. control of the light source based on electronic image signal, light conditioning specially adapted for the ESLM, or </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>for controlling other camera functions, e.g. exposure, shaking by influencing optical parts of the camera (generation of control signals for focussing for optical elements <class-ref scheme="cpc">G02B7/28</class-ref>; using such signals to control focus of particular apparatus, see the subclasses for the apparatus, e.g. <class-ref scheme="cpc">G03B</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">G03F</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04N</class-ref>); </note-paragraph></subnote></note-paragraph></subnote></note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>electronic image data storage (data storage in general <class-ref scheme="cpc">G11B</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">G11C</class-ref>); </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>in-camera image processing e.g. correction of lens distortion, defect pixel correction, noise suppression, removal of motion blur, improving of the dynamic range of the image, in-projector image processing, electronic image data manipulation, e.g. during display or projection (image processing per se <class-ref scheme="cpc">G06T</class-ref>); </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>electronic viewfinders e.g. control of image pickup devices based on information indicated by the electronic viewfinder displaying an image signal generated by the EIS ; </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>electrica or mechanical aspects of camera modules using electronic image sensors, as well as related constructional details as in webcams or mobile phones (see <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04M1/0264</class-ref> for mounting structure in mobile phones); </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>details of projectors peculiar to the use of an ESLM, e.g. dichroic or polarizing arrangements specially adapted for the ESLM (dichroic or polarizing arrangements in general <class-ref scheme="cpc">G02B</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">G03B</class-ref>); </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>remote control of cameras or projectors peculiar to the EIS or the ESLM, e.g. affecting their operation, or based on a generated image signal; </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>adaptations peculiar to the use of a EIS or ESLM and/or the display, the transmission, recording or other use of electrical image data and related circuitry, e.g. mounting of EIS or ESLM, integrated cleaning system for the EIS, dust mapping, cooling of the EIS, controlling the operation of the EIS by external input signals; </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>systems or apparatus wherein the inventive contribution lies in the interaction between features covered in Notes 1 above, concerning cameras and projectors, when interacting with those covered in Note 1 of <class-ref scheme="cpc">G03B</class-ref>, e.g. switch-over between electronic motion-blur correction of electronic viewfinder during focussing and optical motion-blur correction of the lens during exposure, electronic motion blur correction of the electronic image sensor based on output signals of additional sensor, or interaction between mechanical shutter and electronic control of the charge accumulation period of the EIS;]</note-paragraph></subnote></note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>(in group <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04N1/00</class-ref>) systems for the transmission or the reproduction of arbitrarily composed pictures or patterns in which the local light variations composing a picture are not subject to variation with time, e.g. documents (both written and printed), maps, charts, photographs (other than cinematograph films); </note-paragraph></subnote><subnote><note-paragraph> circuits specially designed for dealing with pictorial communication signals, e.g. television signals, as distinct from merely signals of a particular frequency range. </note-paragraph></subnote> 2. This subclass <u>does not cover</u>: <subnote><note-paragraph>circuits or other parts of systems which form the subject of other subclasses, which are covered by the corresponding subclasses, e.g. <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03C</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03F</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03J</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04B</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04H</class-ref>; </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>systems in which legible alphanumeric or like character forms are analysed according to step (a) of Note (1) to derive an electric signal from which the character is recognised by comparison with stored information, which are covered by subclass <class-ref scheme="cpc">G06K</class-ref>; </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>systems for the direct photographic copying of an original picture in which an electric signal representative of the picture is derived according to the said step (a) of and employed to modify the operation of the system, e.g. to control exposure, which are covered by class <class-ref scheme="cpc">G03</class-ref>; </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>systems for the reproduction according to step (b) of Note (1) of pictures comprising alphanumeric or like character forms but involving the production of the equivalent of a signal which would be derived according to the abovementioned step (a), e.g. by cams, punched card or tape, coded control signal, or other means, which are covered by the subclass for the application, e.g. <class-ref scheme="cpc">G01D</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">G06T</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04L</class-ref>;</note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>systems for the reproduction to the above-mentioned step (b) of pictures comprising alphanumeric or like character forms and involving the generation according to the abovementioned step (a) of picture-representative electric signals from a pre-arranged assembly of such characters, or records thereof, forming an integral part of the systems, which are covered by the subclass for the application, e.g. <class-ref scheme="cpc">B41B</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">G06K</class-ref>, subject to those applications which are covered by this subclass; </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>printing, duplication or marking methods, or materials or processes therefor, which are covered by the relevant subclasses, e.g. <class-ref scheme="cpc">B41C</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">B41M</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">G03C</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">G03F</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">G03G</class-ref>; </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>[N: apparatus or methods for taking photographs using light sensitive film for image capture, apparatus/methods for printing, for projecting or viewing images using film stock, photographic film or slides by optical means, e.g. mounting of optical elements, flashes, and their related controls, e.g. exposure, focus, (opto-)mechanical motion blur (anti-shake), cooling, beam shaping; </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>aspects of apparatus or methods for taking photographs using an electronic image sensor [EIS] for image capture, insofar as they correspond to those of said apparatus methods for taking photographs using light sensitive film, i.e. insofar as not peculiar to the presence of the EIS, e.g. mounting of optical elements or flashes not peculiar to the presence of the EIS, and their related controls insofar as they are not peculiar to the presence or use of the EIS, e.g. exposure, focus, (opto-)mechanical motion blur (anti-shake); </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>aspects of apparatus or methods for projecting or viewing images using an electronic spatial light modulator [ESLM], insofar as they correspond to those of said apparatus/ methods for projecting or viewing images using film stock, photographic film or slides, i.e. insofar as not peculiar to the presence of the ESLM, e.g. mounting of optical elements not peculiar to the presence of the ESLM, and their related controls not peculiar to the presence of the ESLM, e.g. cooling, beam shaping, optical keystone correction; </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>(opto-)mechanical image enhancement in printers or projectors, e.g. keystone correction; </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>optical viewfinders; </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>remote control of cameras and projectors insofar not peculiar to the EIS or ESLM, e.g. not affecting their operation, or being based on a generated image signal; </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>optical aspects of camera modules using electronic image sensors and related constructional details (optical elements or arrangements associated with solid state imager structures <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L27/14625</class-ref>);</note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>constructional aspects of projectors, e.g. cooling, beam shaping, light integrating means not peculiar to the ESLM;] </note-paragraph></subnote> 3. In this subclass, the following expression is used with the meaning indicated: <subnote><note-paragraph>&quot;television systems&quot; means those systems for the <CPC-specific-text> electronic generation</CPC-specific-text>, transmission and reproduction of arbitrarily composed pictures in which the local light variations composing a picture may change with time, e.g. natural &quot;live&quot; scenes, <CPC-specific-text> electronic</CPC-specific-text> recordings of such scenes such as cinematograph films].</note-paragraph></subnote> 4. In this subclass, as in subclass <class-ref scheme="cpc">G03B</class-ref>, the following terms are used with the meaning indicated: <subnote><note-paragraph>&quot;camera&quot;: a device capturing image information represented by light patterns reflected or emitted from objects, and exposing a light sensitive film or a main electronic image sensor during a timed exposure, usually through a photographic lens, and producing an image on a light sensitive film or an electrical image information signal respectively;</note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>&quot;projector&quot;: a device displaying image information by projection of light patterns, usually through an optical lens, wherein the light patterns are generated by illuminating an image, e.g. film or slide, or by converting an electric image signal into an optical signal using an electronic spatial light modulator; </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>&quot;electronic image sensor [EIS]&quot;: optoelectronic transducer, converting optical image information into an electrical signal susceptible of being processed, stored, transmitted or displayed; </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>&quot;additional sensor&quot;: a sensor, other than the main electronic image sensor, used for controlling a camera; </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>&quot;electronic spatial light modulator [ESLM]&quot;: optoelectronic transducer converting electric signals representing image information into optical image information.]</note-paragraph></subnote> </note-paragraph></note><note type="warning"><note-paragraph>The following IPC groups are not used in the CPC scheme. Subject matter covered by these groups is classified in the following CPC groups :<br/><pre>
- <class-ref scheme="not-mapped">H04N5/31</class-ref>    covered by  <class-ref scheme="cpc">G01S7/52</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">G01S15/89</class-ref>
- <class-ref scheme="ipc">H04N5/761</class-ref>   covered by  <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04N5/782</class-ref>
- <class-ref scheme="ipc">H04N5/7613</class-ref>  covered by  <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04N5/782</class-ref>
- <class-ref scheme="ipc">H04N5/7617</class-ref>  covered by  <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04N5/782</class-ref> 
- <class-ref scheme="ipc">H04N5/922</class-ref>   covered by  <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04N5/92</class-ref> 
- <class-ref scheme="ipc">H04N5/924</class-ref>   covered by  <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04N5/92</class-ref> 
- <class-ref scheme="ipc">H04N7/40</class-ref>    covered by  <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04N7/38</class-ref> 
- <class-ref scheme="ipc">H04N7/42</class-ref>    covered by  <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04B14/06</class-ref> 
- <class-ref scheme="ipc">H04N7/44</class-ref>    covered by  <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04B14/06</class-ref> 
- <class-ref scheme="ipc">H04N9/815</class-ref>   covered by  <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04N9/81</class-ref> 
- <class-ref scheme="ipc">H04N11/24</class-ref>   covered by  <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04N11/002</class-ref> 
- <class-ref scheme="ipc">H04N15/00</class-ref>   covered by  <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04N13/00</class-ref></pre> </note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H04Q.xml" sort-key="H04Q" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H04Q</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">SELECTING </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">switches, relays, selectors <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01H</class-ref>; electronic switches <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03K17/00</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass covers: <pre>
- methods, circuits, or apparatus for stablishing selectively <br/>  a connect ion between a desired number of stations (normally <br/>  two), or between a main station and a desired number of <br/>  substations (normally one) for the purpose of transferring <br/>  information via this connection after it has been established; <br/>- selective calling arrangements over connections already <br/>  established.</pre> In either case, the connection may be made by means of electric conductors or electromagnetic waves.</note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>In this subclass, the following terms or expressions are used with the meanings indicated: <pre>
- &quot;subscriber&quot; is a general term for terminal equipment, e.g. telephone for public use;
- &quot;substation&quot; means a subscriber or monitoring equipment which may connect a single subscriber to a line without choice as to subscriber; 
- &quot;satellite&quot; is a kind of exchange the operation of which depends upon control signals received from a supervisory exchange;
- &quot;switching centres&quot; includes exchanges and satellites.</pre> </note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H04R.xml" sort-key="H04R" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H04R</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">LOUDSPEAKERS, MICROPHONES, GRAMOPHONE PICK-UPS OR LIKE ACOUSTIC ELECTROMECHANICAL TRANSDUCERS</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> DEAF-AID SETS</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> PUBLIC ADDRESS SYSTEMS </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">generating mechanical vibrations in general <class-ref scheme="cpc">B06B</class-ref>; transducers for measuring particular variables <class-ref scheme="cpc">G01</class-ref>; transducers in clocks <class-ref scheme="cpc">G04</class-ref>; producing sounds with frequency not determined by supply frequency <class-ref scheme="cpc">G10K</class-ref>; transducers in recording or reproducing heads <class-ref scheme="cpc">G11B</class-ref>; transducers in motors <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass <u>covers</u>: <subnote><note-paragraph>loudspeakers, microphones, <CPC-specific-text> acoustic</CPC-specific-text> transducers <CPC-specific-text> therefor</CPC-specific-text> producing acoustic waves or variations of electric current or voltage, or gramophone pick-ups;</note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>arrangements actuated by variations of electric current or voltage for cutting grooves in records;</note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>circuits for the above-mentioned <CPC-specific-text> loudspeakers, microphones, acoustic transducers, gramophone pick-ups or</CPC-specific-text> arrangements;</note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>monitoring or testing <CPC-specific-text> of the above-mentioned loudspeakers, microphones, acoustic transducers, gramophone pick-ups or arrangements</CPC-specific-text></note-paragraph></subnote> </note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H04S.xml" sort-key="H04S" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H04S</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">STEREOPHONIC SYSTEMS </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">information storage on discs or tapes <class-ref scheme="cpc">G11B</class-ref>; broadcast systems for the distribution of stereophonic information <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04H20/88</class-ref>; multiplex systems in general <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04J</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>In this subclass, the following term is used with the meaning indicated:<br/>- &quot;stereophonic systems&quot; covers quadraphonic or similar systems </note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H04T.xml" sort-key="H04T" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H04T</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">INDEXING SCHEME RELATING TO STANDARDS FOR ELECTRIC COMMUNICATION TECHNIQUE </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">CLASS <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This scheme constitutes an non-associated internal scheme for indexing exclusively documents issued by standardisation bodies (herein called standards) for electric communication technique (H04).<br/>As standardisation bodies organize their documents in different ways, the present scheme is subdivided into main groups related to a particular CPC range to allow different indexing approaches.</note-paragraph><note-paragraph>Scheme index:</note-paragraph><note-paragraph><pre><br/>Wireless communication standards       <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04T2001/00</class-ref> - <class-ref scheme="not-mapped">T04T1/999</class-ref><br/>Standards related to data switching<br/>  networks in general                  <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04T2012/00</class-ref> - <class-ref scheme="not-mapped">T04T12/99</class-ref><br/>Internet standards                     <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04T2029/00</class-ref> - <class-ref scheme="not-mapped">T04T29/99</class-ref></pre></note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H04W.xml" sort-key="H04W" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H04W</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">WIRELESS COMMUNICATIONS NETWORKS </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">radio transmission systems <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04B7/00</class-ref>; transmission systems using electromagnetic waves other than radio waves, e.g. light, infrared <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04B10/00</class-ref>; communication systems using wireless extensions, i.e. wireless links without selective communication, e.g. cordless telephones <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04M1/72</class-ref>; broadcast communication <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04H</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass <u>covers</u>: <subnote><note-paragraph>communication networks for selectively establishing one or a plurality of wireless communication links between a desired number of users or between users and network equipment, for the purpose of transferring information via these wireless communication links; </note-paragraph></subnote><subnote><note-paragraph>networks deploying an infrastructure for mobility management of wireless users connected thereto, e.g. cellular networks, WLAN [Wireless Local Area Network], wireless access networks, e.g. WLL [Wireless Local Loop] or self-organising wireless communication networks, e.g. ad hoc networks; </note-paragraph></subnote><subnote><note-paragraph>planning or deployment specially adapted for the above-mentioned wireless networks; </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>services or facilities specially adapted for the above-mentioned wireless networks; </note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>arrangements or echniques specially adapted for the operation of the above-mentioned wireless networks.</note-paragraph></subnote></note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>This subclass <u>does not cover</u>: <subnote><note-paragraph>communication systems using wireless extensions, i.e. wireless links without selective communication, e.g. cordless telephones, which are covered by group <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04M1/72</class-ref>;</note-paragraph></subnote> <subnote><note-paragraph>broadcast communication, which is covered by subclass <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04H</class-ref>. </note-paragraph></subnote></note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>In this subclass, at each hierarchical level, in the absence of an indication to the contrary, classification is made in the first appropriate place. </note-paragraph><note-paragraph> </note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> </classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="4" additional-only="false" sort-key="H05" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H05</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">ELECTRIC TECHNIQUES NOT OTHERWISE PROVIDED FOR</text></title-part></class-title> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H05B.xml" sort-key="H05B" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H05B</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">ELECTRIC HEATING</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> ELECTRIC LIGHTING NOT OTHERWISE PROVIDED FOR </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">apparatus for special application, see the relevant places, e.g. <class-ref scheme="cpc">A47J</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">C21</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">C22</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">C23</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">F21</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">F24</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">F27</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>Attention is drawn to the Note (paragraph III) following the contents of Section of Section H </note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H05C.xml" sort-key="H05C" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H05C</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">ELECTRIC CIRCUITS OR APPARATUS SPECIALLY DESIGNED FOR USE IN EQUIPMENT FOR KILLING, STUNNING, OR GUIDING LIVING BEINGS </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">stationary means for catching or killing insects by electric means <class-ref scheme="cpc">A01M1/22</class-ref>; apparatus for the destruction of noxious animals, other than insects, by electricity <class-ref scheme="cpc">A01M19/00</class-ref>; electric traps for animals <class-ref scheme="cpc">A01M23/38</class-ref>; scaring devices for animals <class-ref scheme="cpc">A01M29/00</class-ref>; slaughtering or stunning by electric current <class-ref scheme="cpc">A22B3/06</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H05F.xml" sort-key="H05F" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H05F</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">STATIC ELECTRICITY</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> NATURALLY-OCCURRING ELECTRICITY </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">electrostatic machines <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02N</class-ref>; uses of electricity in performing operations, e.g. precipitation, see the relevant subclasses for the operations</text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass covers methods or arrangements for preventing the formation of electrostatic charges on bodies or for carrying-off these charges after their formation.</note-paragraph> <note-paragraph>This subclass does not cover specific applications of the above-mentioned methods or arrangements, e.g. during the manufacture of artificial fibres or films, which are covered by the relevant subclasses.</note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H05G.xml" sort-key="H05G" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H05G</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">X-RAY TECHNIQUE </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">apparatus for radiation diagnosis <class-ref scheme="cpc">A61B6/00</class-ref>; X-ray therapy <class-ref scheme="cpc">A61N</class-ref>; testing by X-rays <class-ref scheme="cpc">G01N</class-ref>; apparatus for X-ray photography <class-ref scheme="cpc">G03B</class-ref>; filters, conversion screens, microscopes <class-ref scheme="cpc">G21K</class-ref>; X-ray tubes <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J35/00</class-ref>; TV systems having X-ray input <class-ref scheme="cpc">H04N5/321</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="warning"><note-paragraph>The following IPC group is not used in the CPC scheme. <class-ref scheme="ipc">H05G1/61</class-ref> covered by <class-ref scheme="cpc">H05G1/60</class-ref> </note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H05H.xml" sort-key="H05H" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H05H</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">PLASMA TECHNIQUE </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">fusion reactors <class-ref scheme="cpc">G21B</class-ref>; ion-beam tubes <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01J27/00</class-ref>; magnetohydrodynamic generators <class-ref scheme="cpc">H02K44/08</class-ref>; producing X-rays involving plasma generation <class-ref scheme="cpc">H05G2/00</class-ref></text></reference></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> PRODUCTION OF ACCELERATED ELECTRICALLY-CHARGED PARTICLES OR OF NEUTRONS </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">obtaining neutrons from radioactive sources <class-ref scheme="cpc">G21</class-ref>, e.g. <class-ref scheme="cpc">G21B</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">G21C</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">G21G</class-ref></text></reference></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> PRODUCTION OR ACCELERATION OF NEUTRAL MOLECULAR OR ATOMIC BEAMS </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">atomic clocks <class-ref scheme="cpc">G04F5/14</class-ref>; devices using stimulated emission <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01S</class-ref>; frequency regulation by comparison with a reference frequency determined by energy levels of molecules, atoms, or subatomic particles <class-ref scheme="cpc">H03L7/26</class-ref></text></reference></title-part></class-title></classification-item> 
<classification-item breakdown-code="false" not-allocatable="true" level="5" additional-only="false" link-file="cpc-H05K.xml" sort-key="H05K" date-revised="2013-01-01"><classification-symbol>H05K</classification-symbol><class-title date-revised="2013-01-01"><title-part><text scheme="ipc">PRINTED CIRCUITS</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> CASINGS OR CONSTRUCTIONAL DETAILS OF ELECTRIC APPARATUS</text></title-part><title-part><text scheme="ipc"> MANUFACTURE OF ASSEMBLAGES OF ELECTRICAL COMPONENTS </text><reference><text scheme="ipc">details of instruments or comparable details of other apparatus not otherwise provided for <class-ref scheme="cpc">G12B</class-ref>; thin-film or thick-film circuits <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L27/01</class-ref>, <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01L27/13</class-ref>; non-printed means for electric connections to or between printed circuits, </text><CPC-specific-text><text scheme="cpc"> electric connections or line connectors, apparatus or processes for manufacturing, assembling, maintaining or repairing such connections or connectors</text></CPC-specific-text><text scheme="ipc"> <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01R</class-ref>; casings for, or constructional details of, particular types of apparatus, see the relevant subclasses; processes involving only a single technical art, e.g. heating, spraying, for which provision exists elsewhere, see the relevant classes</text></reference></title-part></class-title><notes-and-warnings date-revised="2013-01-01"><note type="note"><note-paragraph>This subclass covers:<pre>
- combinations of a radio or television receiver with apparatus having a different main function;- printed circuits structurally associated with non-printed electric components;
- <CPC-specific-text> printed connectors (non printed connectors <class-ref scheme="cpc">H01R</class-ref>)</CPC-specific-text></pre></note-paragraph><note-paragraph><br/></note-paragraph><note-paragraph>In this subclass, the following expression is used with the meaning indicated: <pre>- &quot;printed circuits&quot; covers all kinds of mechanical constructions of circuits that consist of an insulating base or support carrying the conductor and are combined structurally with the conductor throughout their length, especially in a two-dimensional plane, the conductors of which are secured to the base in a non-dismountable manner, and also covers the processes or apparatus for manufacturing such constructions, e.g. forming the circuit by mechanical or chemical treatment of a conductive foil, paste, or film on an insulating support.</pre></note-paragraph></note></notes-and-warnings></classification-item> </classification-item> </classification-item> </classification-item> </class-scheme>
